careerbuilder.ca 2016-05-04

# Find Jobs on CareerBuilder.com

### Effective Date: June 25, 2014

## Overview

CareerBuilder Canada Co. and its parent company, CareerBuilder, LLC and its parent company’s divisions (collectively, “CareerBuilder”, “We” or “Our”) has drafted this Privacy Policy to provide you notice of our data and security practices and policies as you use CareerBuilder websites and Apps (the “Sites”). This Privacy Policy describes the types of Personal Information we collect, how we use the information, with whom we share it, and the choices you can make about our collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information. The phrase “Personal Information” refers to information that may be used to personally identify you, such as your name, address, telephone number, email address, credit card number or other billing information. We also describe the measures we take to help protect the security of your Personal Information and how you can contact us about our privacy practices. Please do not provide us with highly sensitive information, such as Social Insurance Numbers, financial information or health records.

Please review this Privacy Policy periodically as we may update it from time to time without prior notice to reflect changes in our data practices. We will post a prominent notice on our Sites to notify you of any significant changes to our Privacy Policy and indicate at the bottom of the notice when it was most recently updated. If we make material changes to the policy that will affect previously collected Personal Information, you will be notified and asked to consent to the updated Privacy Policy. 

Click on one of the links below to jump directly to the listed section:

  * Information We Collect
  * How We Use the Information We Collect
  * Information We Share
  * Resume Privacy Options
  * Cookies and Third-party Advertisers
  * Update Your Account Information 
  * Links to Other Websites
  * International Data Transfers
  * How We Protect Personal Information
  * Some Important Tips To Use When Dealing With Prospective Employers
  * How to Contact Us

### Information We Collect

We may obtain information about you from various sources, including our Sites, when you call or email us or communicate with us through social media, or when you participate in events, contests or other promotions. We also may obtain information about you from our parent, affiliate or subsidiary companies, business partners and other third parties and publicly available information.

The types of information we may obtain include:

  * Your Personal Information, if you choose to provide it or if we obtain it in the manner described above. You do not have to give us any Personal Information in order to perform job searches or to read the content portions of the Sites.
  * Username and password for the account you may establish on our Sites.
  * Payment details (including payment card number, security code, expiration date, cardholder name and billing address) if you represent a Company that is buying our products through our Sites.
  * Your demographic information (such as zip or postal code, occupation, education and experience, and if you choose to provide it, age, gender and race or ethnicity). We collect this information either through the registration process, from your resume or in the manner described above. 
  * Job search behavior and preferences, and a record of the searches that you make on our Sites. We do this in order to present you with job recommendations based on your interests as expressed previously through your searches. 
  * Other details that you may submit to us or that may be included in the information provided to us by third parties.

We collect information stored in your social media profile that you authorize us to access when you use your social media profile to enact features on the Sites, such as the ability to pre-populate our registration form or a job application. CareerBuilder provides software applications (“Apps”) available to the public. If you decide to download one of our Apps, we will collect your profile information, including your social network site user ID, work email address, name, city, state, social network site profile image URL, and employment history, including job titles and company names. 

In addition, when you visit our Sites or use our Apps, we may collect certain information by automated means, such as cookies and web beacons, as described in more detail below. The information we may collect by automated means includes:

  * Information about the devices our visitors use to access the Internet (such as the IP address and the device, browser and operating system type).
  * Pages and URLs that refer visitors to our Sites, also pages and URLs that visitors exit to once they leave our Sites.
  * Dates and times of visits to our Sites.
  * Information on actions taken on our Sites (such as page views, site navigation patterns and job view or application activity).
  * A general geographic location (such as country and city) from which a visitor accesses our Sites.
  * Search terms that visitors use to reach our Sites.

(Return to Top)

### How We Use the Information We Collect

We may use the information we obtain about you to:

  * Register, manage and maintain your account on the Sites.
  * Provide products or services you request.
  * Process, validate and deliver your purchases (including by processing payment card transactions and contacting you about your orders, including by telephone).
  * Maintain a record of the jobs you view or apply to on our Sites. 
  * Inform you of relevant job postings that may be of interest to you.
  * Provide administrative notices or communications applicable to your use of the Sites.
  * Respond to your questions and comments and provide customer support.
  * Contact you and deliver marketing and promotional communications to you by email, text message or other means that, in some cases, is targeted to your interests (such as the CareerBuilder Newsletter, Career Fair Announcements, Product & Sponsor Information, relevant services, educational or other career development opportunities); enable you to communicate with us; and solicit your feedback and input. These communications will contain links for preference management and, where appropriate, unsubscribe links should you decide you do not want to receive further communications. Please note that if you unsubscribe from receiving marketing and promotional communications from CareerBuilder, you may continue to receive transactional and operational emails from us.
  * Manage your participation in our events and other promotions, where you have signed up for such events and promotions.
  * Operate, evaluate and improve our business and the products and services we offer.
  * Analyze and enhance our marketing communications and strategies (including by identifying when emails we have sent to you have been received and read).
  * Analyze trends and statistics regarding visitors’ use of our Sites, mobile applications and social media assets, and the jobs viewed or applied to on our Sites. 
  * Protect against and prevent fraud, unauthorized transactions, claims and other liabilities, and manage risk exposure, including by identifying potential hackers and other unauthorized users.
  * Enforce our Sites’ [Terms and Conditions](http://www.careerbuilder.ca/intl/share/info/termsconditions.aspx).
  * Comply with applicable legal requirements and industry standards and our policies.

We also use certain technical information about your computer and your access of the Sites (including your internet protocol address) in order to operate, maintain and manage the Sites. We collect this information by automated means, such as cookies and web beacons, as described in more detail below. 

(Return to Top)

### INFORMATION WE SHARE

When you apply for a job through the Sites or publicly post your resume to our resume database, employers will have access to information about you (including your e-mail address and other contact information that you publish on your resume) and your potential interest in employment opportunities. Those employers may use your information to contact you directly at the contact information you have provided. Additionally, when you apply for a job through the Sites, the information supplied by you becomes part of the CareerBuilder database but also may become part of the employer’s database. Similarly, if your resume is downloaded by an employer, your resume may become a part of the employer’s database. In these instances, the use of such information by the employer will be subject to the privacy policy of that company, and we are not responsible for that company’s use of your information. 

Additionally, we may combine certain Aggregate Data about our users and use such Aggregate Data to prepare reports for our users (typically employers or educators). “Aggregate Data” is the demographic information (such as postal code, age, gender) and employment information (such as occupation, education and experience) of many individuals that is combined together. Aggregate Data is used to analyze the characteristics of various populations. For example, an employer may purchase a report from CareerBuilder that states the number of accountants with at least five years’ experience that live within a certain geographic area. 

Other than instances where users opt to publicly post their Personal Information to our resume database, provide it via a job application, include it in a job posting or otherwise provide permission to share it, we do not sell our users' Personal Information to anyone for any reason. When posting jobs and resumes, our users decide for themselves how much contact information they wish to display. All users should be aware, however, that when they choose to display or distribute Personal Information (such as their email address or other contact information on a public resume) via the Sites or any other distribution method, that information can be collected and used by others. This may result in unsolicited messages from third parties, for which CareerBuilder is not responsible. 

Where you have provided Personal Information on a Site that is “hosted” or ”co-branded” by another company then that information will be made available to both CareerBuilder and the hosting/co-branding company. CareerBuilder is not responsible for what the hosting/co-branding company, or any third party with whom you may share your Personal Information, subsequently does with your information. You should review the privacy policy of the hosting/co-branding company to ensure that you are comfortable with how it intends to use and disclose your information. 

We also may share Personal Information with our service providers who help us in the delivery of our own products and services to you. These service providers may only use or disclose the information as necessary to perform services on our behalf or as otherwise required by law.

CareerBuilder also may disclose specific user information when we determine, in good faith, that such disclosure is necessary to comply with the law, to cooperate with or seek assistance from law enforcement, to prevent a crime or protect national security, or to protect the interests or safety of CareerBuilder or other users of the Sites. 

In addition, Personal Information we have collected may be passed on to a third party in the event of a transfer of ownership or assets or a bankruptcy or other corporate reorganization of CareerBuilder. 

(Return to Top)

### Resume Privacy Options

Posting your resume on the Sites puts you in front of thousands of employers with open positions each day. When you post your resume, we automatically create a registration for you using the email address and password that you supply. When you return to the Sites in the future you will use that same email address and password to access and edit your existing resume.

We know that our job seekers have varying levels of comfort when it comes to posting their resume on the Internet. To accommodate the needs of all users, CareerBuilder has 2 levels of resume privacy from which you can choose. Please note that these privacy settings only apply to whether or not your resume can be viewed by third parties. CareerBuilder will still collect, use or disclose Aggregate Data about you and your visits to our website in the manner described in this Privacy Policy.

  1. ### Standard Posting

This option gives you the most visibility to the broadest employer audience possible by making your resume searchable in our resume database. If you select this option, any registered employer user who purchases access to the database can view your resume and contact details (to the extent you include them in your resume). 
  2. ### Private Posting For Apply Online Only

This option allows you to post your resume on the Sites without having it searchable by or viewable to employers. The benefit is that you can quickly and easily apply for jobs without retyping your information, and you provide your resume only to those employers you are specifically interested in.

We attempt to limit access to our searchable resume database to legitimate users such as paying employers, recruiters, hiring managers, headhunters and human resource professionals, but cannot guarantee that other parties will not gain access to this database. We cannot control the use of resumes by third parties who access such resumes while they are in our searchable database. You may remove your resume from our searchable database at any time. However, employers, recruiters and others who have paid for access to that database, as well as parties who have otherwise gained access to the database may have retained a copy of your resume in their own files or databases. We cannot control the retention, use or privacy of resumes or profiles that have been downloaded by third parties. Accordingly, you should not put information you would not want made public in your resume.

(Return to Top)

### About Cookies, Tracking Choices, and Third Party Advertisers

A “cookie" is a text file that websites send to a visitor‘s computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify the visitor’s browser or to store information or settings in the browser. A “web beacon," is also called a Web bug or a pixel tag or a clear GIF. Used in combination with cookies, a Web beacon is an often-transparent graphic image, usually no larger than 1 pixel x 1 pixel, that is placed on a Web site or in an e-mail that is used to monitor the behavior of the user visiting the Web site or sending the e-mail.

CareerBuilder uses cookies and other similar technologies for the convenience of our users. Cookies enable us to serve secure pages to our users without asking them to sign in repeatedly. CareerBuilder also stores information about you such as past jobs viewed and job searches conducted by your computer. We do this in order to present you with job recommendations based on your interests as expressed previously through your searches. Lastly, CareerBuilder uses cookies to ensure the proper functioning and efficiency of our Sites. Most Internet browsers enable you to erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please be aware, however, that some CareerBuilder features or services may not function properly without cookies.

CareerBuilder permits third party cookies on its Sites. For example, third party tools located on the Sites, including those that allow for social media sharing, may use cookies to remember user preference settings. CareerBuilder also uses web analytics services provided by third parties, which use cookies to collect information about details of our users’ visits to the Sites (including IP addresses) and the resources they access on the Sites. These third party web analytics services provide us with reports based on this information in order to help us understand how visitors engage with the Sites. 

We use third-party advertising companies who may place or access cookies on your computer hard drive to distinguish your web browser uniquely and to keep track of information relating to serving ads on your web browser, such as the type of ads shown and the webs pages on which the ads appeared. These companies may use information about your visits to our Sites and to other sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you on our Sites or on other, third party, sites. You may opt-out of the collection and use of your information for such purposes by clicking the “Ad Choices” icon located within the ad or by accessing the [“about ads” opt-out site](http://www.youradchoices.ca/choices). Please note that this opt-out is cookie-based. If you buy a new computer, change web browsers or delete this cookie, you will need to perform the opt-out task again. To obtain instructions regarding deleting or disabling cookies from third party advertising companies that are not members of the About Ads or NAI self-regulatory behavioral ad opt-out groups, please [click here](http://www.careerbuilder.ca/Jobseeker/Page.aspx?pagever=remove-cookies). Our site does not respond to web browser do not track signals.

We also may give third party advertisers the ability to tailor their advertisements on our Sites using demographic and preference information we provide to them in aggregate form. This information does not identify you individually. 

These companies operate under their own privacy policies and CareerBuilder encourages you to be aware of the privacy policies of such companies. CareerBuilder does not have control over or access to any information contained in the cookies that are set on your computer by third party advertisers. 

In addition, some of the employers that use our Sites may place cookies on your computer through their job postings and may use such cookies to distinguish your web browser uniquely. Often, employers use such information to track the effectiveness of their job postings by measuring how many users who view their postings later became job applicants. To obtain guidance regarding deleting or disabling cookies, please [click here](http://www.careerbuilder.ca/Jobseeker/Page.aspx?pagever=remove-cookies). 

### Update Your Account Information

You may access, update and amend Personal Information in our custody or control at any time by logging into your account and making the necessary changes or by contacting us at the contact information set out at the end of this Privacy Policy. You may also delete your resume from our resume database at any time by logging in to your account and deleting the resume. Deleting your resume will remove it from your account and from the resume database, however; if you have applied to a job in the past, that particular employer will still be able to access your resume. Further, you will not be able to delete data held by third parties, such as prospective employers, that have already accessed and downloaded your information or resume.

(Return to Top)

### Links to Other Websites

Our Sites may contain links to other sites for your convenience and information. These sites may be operated by companies not owned by CareerBuilder. In addition, if you are using our App through a social networking site, remember that our Apps may be served by or hosted by other sites. These other sites or linked third-party sites may have their own privacy notices, which you should review if you visit those sites. We are not responsible for the content of any sites not owned by CareerBuilder, any use of those sites, or those sites’ privacy practices.

(Return to Top)

### International Data Transfers

When we obtain Personal Information about you, we or our service providers may process and store the information outside of the country in which you are located, including in the United States. The countries in which we process the information may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you are located. Further, users who access your information, such as potential employers, also may be located in a different country than you and different laws may apply to their use of your information.

(Return to Top)

### How We Protect Personal Information

CareerBuilder maintains administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to assist us in protecting the Personal Information we collect against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use. 

Please note that no electronic transmission of information can be entirely secure. We cannot guarantee that the security measures we have in place to safeguard Personal Information will never be defeated or fail, or that those measures will always be sufficient or effective. Therefore, although we are committed to protecting your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your Personal Information will always remain private. As a user of the Sites, you understand and agree that you assume all responsibility and risk for your use of the Sites, the internet generally, and the documents you post or access and for your conduct on and off the Sites.

Please note that no electronic transmission of information can be entirely secure. We cannot guarantee that the security measures we have in place to safeguard Personal Information will never be defeated or fail, or that those measures will always be sufficient or effective. Therefore, although we are committed to protecting your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your Personal Information will always remain private. As a user of the Sites, you understand and agree that you assume all responsibility and risk for your use of the Sites, the internet generally, and the documents you post or access and for your conduct on and off the Sites. You should safeguard your CareerBuilder account user name and password and not share that information with anyone. You may not provide your password or otherwise permit access to your CareerBuilder account to any third party. You are responsible for all uses of your account, whether or not authorized by you. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your information and password. You agree to protect and keep your password confidential, to change your password on a regular basis, and to maintain appropriate and regularly updated malware scanning and cleaning tools on your network and individual computer(s). You should also sign off your account and close your browser window when you have finished your visit to our Sites. Please note that we will never ask for your CareerBuilder account user name or password via email. You agree to notify CareerBuilder immediately of any unauthorized use of your account or password. 

(Return to Top)

### Some Important Tips To Use When Dealing With Prospective Employers

  * You should use your own careful judgment about whether and what information to provide prospective employers.
  * DO NOT PUT SENSITIVE INFORMATION, SUCH AS YOUR SOCIAL INSURANCE NUMBER, ON YOUR RESUME.
  * CareerBuilder’s Sites are open to the public, and we cannot guarantee that all users of our services have a legitimate need to the information they seek. If you do not wish to be contacted electronically by prospective employers, do not publish your email or other electronic address in your resume posted on our Sites. 
  * Do not provide your social insurance number, national identification number or any state, provincial or other local identification number to a prospective employer via online application. Identity thieves may attempt to trick you into providing sensitive information. Do not provide any non-work related Personal Information (i.e., your social insurance number or any other state or national identification number, eye color, marital status, etc.) over the phone or online.
  * Job seekers should never provide credit card or bank numbers or engage in a monetary transaction of any sort. 
  * Be cautious when dealing with contacts outside of your own country. 

For additional details regarding How To Spot Fraud Online, please [click here.](http://www.careerbuilder.com/JobSeeker/Info/privacy.aspx?version=fraud)

We use secure socket layer (or “SSL”) technology to protect credit card transactions. The SSL technology encrypts credit card numbers while in transit to help ensure that they are not intercepted by unintended third parties. We use BluePay Processing LLC to process credit card purchases and their privacy policy may be viewed [here.](http://www.bluepay.com/privacy-policy)

(Return to Top)

### How to Contact Us

You can direct questions regarding this Privacy Policy, or the manner in which we or our service providers treat your Personal Information, to CareerBuilder by emailing us at [customer.service@careerbuilder.com](mailto:customer.service@careerbuilder.com) or by letter to CareerBuilder at 5550-A Peachtree Parkway, Norcross, Georgia 30092, Attention: Customer Service. Please include your name and email address in email requests, and your name and postal address in mail requests so that we can respond to you.

(Return to Top)
